campingtourist.com 2019-06-06

# Privacy policy - Camping Tourist

At CampingTourist, we take online privacy seriously and we respect the concerns of our community of users. In this policy, we describe our privacy practices with regard to information we collect through CampingTourist.com and affiliated sites and email properties (collectively, the “Site”) to help you make informed decisions about how you share information when you visit or use the Site.

**Understanding How Information Is Collected on CampingTourist:**

Information You May Choose to Provide to Us

We may collect information, including personally identifiable information, directly from you if you choose to provide that information. For example, you may provide us with your name and contact information (such as an email address), date of birth, or other details of that nature, when you sign up for our newsletters or participate in contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions or surveys on the Site, or apply for a job with CampingTourist.

You also may choose to provide personally identifiable information about yourself when you participate in forums or discussions or other Interactive Services on the Site. Please be aware that information you post may be viewed or captured by anyone who visits the Site, therefore you should avoid posting sensitive or personal information that you would not want to be available to the public.

**Information That Is Automatically Collected When You Visit CampingTourist**

When you access the Site, we and our third-party partners and vendors may automatically collect certain information from your device or web-browser about your visit using tools such as cookies, web beacons, and other data collecting and tracking technologies to help us understand how our users use the Sites and to target advertising messages to you. We and our third-party partners and service providers may also collect and track information about your online activities over time and across different websites, applications, and devices using certain data matching techniques. The information collected automatically when you visit the Site may include your IP address, characteristics of your operating system, information about your browser and system settings, data about the computer or mobile device you use to access the Site, unique device identifiers, clickstream data (which shows the page-by-page path you take as you browse the Site), and other details that generally are not considered personally identifiable.

**Cookies and Tracking Technologies**

Cookies are small files that websites and other online services use to store information about users on the users’ own computers. This Site may use cookies (such as HTTP and HTML5 cookies and Flash cookies), as well as other types of local storage. For more information about cookies, you may visit http://www.allaboutcookies.org . See the section below regarding Your choices to learn more about how you may limit or disable cookies on your computer. If you choose to disable cookies, that could affect certain features of the Site that use cookies to enhance their functionality.

To manage our automatic data collection, we may place tags (often referred to as “web beacons” or “pixel tags”) and other tracking mechanisms on pages on the Site, in videos, or in emails we send to you. Web beacons are small files that link web pages to particular web servers and their cookies, and they may be used for a variety of purposes, such as counting the number of visitors to the Site, analyzing how users navigate around the Site, assessing how many emails that we send are actually opened and which articles or links are viewed by visitors.

We also use third-party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics, on the Site to provide us with statistics and other information about visitors to the Site. Click here to learn more about Google Analytics and how you may opt out.

“Do Not Track” Signals. Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “do not track” signal to websites and online services you visit. At this time there is no consensus among industry participants as to the meaning of “do not track” in this context. Like many other websites, CampingTourist.com is not configured to respond to “do not track” signals from browsers. Click here to learn more about “do not track” signals.

Finally, companies that provide certain third-party apps, tools, widgets, and plug-ins that may appear on the Sites (for example, Facebook “Like” or “Share” buttons) also may use automated means to collect information regarding your interactions with these features. This information collection is subject to the privacy policies or notices of those third parties.

**Information We Receive From Other Sources**

We may supplement the information we collect with information from third-party partners and service providers, including data brokers, customer acquisition vendors, and other companies that collect contact and consumer information such as demographic and interest data, outside sources in order to learn more about our users, to better tailor the content and offers we make available to you, and for other lawful business purposes. We may receive this information about you from third parties, including without limitation data resellers and advertisers. We may combine the information we receive from those other (online and offline) sources with information we collect through the Site.

**Social Network and Platform Integration**

The Sites may be integrated with social media networks and other platforms whereby information may be shared between us and those platforms. For instance, if you interact with our Sites through a social media feature such as a plug-in, then you may be granting us on-going access to certain information from that social media account. If you do not want a social media platform to collect or share information about you, please review the privacy policy and privacy settings of the applicable social media property before using such features on our Sites.

**How We May Use Information We Collect**

We (and our partners) may use the information gathered on CampingTourist for various purposes, including the purposes listed below. For example, if you were to contact us with a question and provide your email address, we would use the email address you provided to respond to your inquiry. In addition, we use information we collect from you and through the Site to:

Provide products and services you request (such as when you sign up to receive our email newsletters) or that we otherwise believe would interest you, including promotional offers from us and our third-party partners;  
Respond to requests, questions, and comments, and provide other types of user support and customer care;  
Offer you products and services, or direct you to portions of this Site or other websites, that we believe may interest you;  
Customize content, features, advertisements or other marketing messages we and third parties show you, both on the Site and elsewhere online;  
Process and reply to applications for employment with CampingTourist;  
Communicate about, and administer your participation in, events, programs, contests, sweepstakes, and other offers or promotions;  
Carry out, evaluate, and improve our business (which may include without limitation developing new features for the Site; analyzing and enhancing the user experience on the Site; assessing the effectiveness of our marketing and advertising; and managing our communications);  
Perform data analytics regarding usage of the Site (including market and customer research, trend analysis, financial analysis, and anonymization of personal information);  
Guard against identity theft, and prevent fraud and other criminal activity, claims, and other liabilities;  
Comply with applicable legal requirements, law enforcement requests, and our company policies; and For other purposes that are disclosed at the time you provide your information, with your consent.

**How We May Share Information**

Our agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers may have access to information we collect through the Site to carry out work on our behalf. In addition, certain service providers may collect or access information through the Site to enable or provide services, tools, or other features available on the Site. We also may share information:

With our affiliates for internal business purposes;  
With third parties for marketing purposes, including social media networks, data management platforms, and other advertising technology providers; for example, we may match your email address with third parties with whom you have also consented to share your email address and use such match to deliver custom offers or emails to you on the Sites and elsewhere online;  
If we are required to do so by law, regulation, or legal process (such as a court order or subpoena);  
In response to requests from government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities;  
If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity;  
With respect to analytics and statistical information, to inform advertisers about the nature of our user base;  
In the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including a reorganization, dissolution, or liquidation); and  
With your consent or at your discretion.  
Your Choices

**Unsubscribe from emails.**

To unsubscribe from a particular newsletter, click the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of that email newsletter. If you would like to globally opt-out from all CampingTourist email campaigns, please send an email to optout@CampingTourist.com with “Unsubscribe” in the subject line. When we send newsletters and marketing messages to subscribers we may allow advertisers or partners to include messages in those newsletters, or we may send dedicated newsletters on behalf of those advertisers or partners. We may disclose your opt-out choices to third parties so that they can honor your preferences in accordance with applicable laws.

**Blocking cookies.**

Certain browsers may be configured to notify you when you receive cookies, or allow you to restrict or disable certain cookies. If you choose to disable cookies, however, that could affect certain features of the Site that use cookies to enhance their functionality.

**Disabling local shared objects (“Flash cookies”).**

We may use other kinds of local storage that function similarly, but are stored in different parts of your computer from ordinary browser cookies, including Flash cookies placed on your device or web browser via the Adobe flash plug-in. Your browser may allow you to disable its HTML5 local storage or delete information contained in its HTML5 local storage. Click here for details about deleting information contained in “local shared objects” or adjusting related preferences.

**Options concerning third-party ad networks.**

For more information about third-party ad networks and services that use these technologies, you can visit www.aboutads.info and click here to opt out or to learn more about your options. You also may visit the NAI’s site for additional options on how to opt out of interest-based advertising.

**How We Protect Personal Information.**

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure, or use. That said, it is not possible to guarantee the security of information transmitted online, and you assume some risk with regard to the security of information you provide through any website, including this Site.

Links From CampingTourist to Other Websites.

On this Site, we may provide links to other websites that are controlled by third parties. Linked websites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review. We are not responsible for the content, usage terms, privacy policies, or any other aspects of websites that we do not own or control.

**Surveys, Quizzes and Other Features.**

While you are visiting CampingTourist, you may have the opportunity to participate in surveys or quizzes, or to use other interactive features, including any Interactive Services, that request information about you and your opinions and preferences. Your participation in these features is entirely voluntary. If you do choose to participate, please be aware that these features may be operated by a third party that is not controlled by CampingTourist, and therefore the information you provide may be collected by the third party and subject to its privacy policy.

**Children’s Privacy.**

This Site is not designed or intended for use by children, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete any such information.

**Information for Users Outside the United States.**

If you are visiting CampingTourist from outside the United States, please be aware that information we collect through the Site will be transferred to and stored on our servers in the United States. By using this Site, you acknowledge and consent to the transfer and processing of your personal data in the United States as described in this online privacy policy. Please be aware that the data protection laws and regulations applicable to your personal data transferred to the United States may be different from the laws in your country of residence.

**Our Notice to California Residents.**

Subject to certain limits, under California law California residents may ask us to provide them with a list of the categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, as well as the identity of those third parties. California residents may contact us as specified in the How to Contact Us section below to make a request for this information.

How We’ll Inform You About Changes to This Privacy Policy.

We may update this online privacy policy periodically to reflect changes to our privacy practices, such as how we collect or use personal information. We will indicate at the top of this privacy policy the date when it was most recently updated.

**How to Contact Us.**

If you have questions about this policy or about our privacy practices, you may contact us by emailing privacy@CampingTourist.com. If you are a California resident inquiring about your California privacy rights, please include “California privacy rights request” in the subject line of your email.
